pika97 commented on 5 Jul 2019 •
edited
How to reproduce the behaviour
I have annotated about 600 sentences for NER in the spacy format.
When I run the evaluate function, on the data it shows 0 for all values except token_acc.
I tried to run it for individual sentences, it shows 100 for some ad 0 for the others.
Function I'm using:
import spacy 
from spacy.gold import GoldParse
from spacy.scorer import Scorer 

def evaluate(ner_model,examples):
 scorer = Scorer()
 for input_,annot in examples:
  doc_gold_text = ner_model.make_doc(input_)
  gold = GoldParse(doc_gold_text,entities = annot['entities'])
  pred_value = ner_model(input_)
  scorer.score(pred_value,gold)
  return scorer.scores,gold
Individual results (ie per sentence)
Correct (ie P =100 R=100 F=100):
('with the assistance of the canadian red cross, city staff quickly mobilized to provide reception centres for those torontonians who were without power.', {'entities': [(115, 127, 'NORP')]})
Incorrect(ie P=0 R=0 F= 0)
('b province of new brunswick preparedness, response and recovery december 2013 ice storm after action review report 5 august 2014 final version presented to: mr. greg maccallum director new brunswick emergency measures organization po box 6000 364 argyle street, room 3-92 fredericton, new brunswick e3b 5h1 prepared by: jim bruce atlantic security group inc 33 paul thomas drive dartmouth, nova scotia, b2w 6a1 0c table of contents executive summary .', {'entities': [(17, 30, 'GPE'), (66, 90, 'EVENT'), (120, 134, 'DATE'), (168, 187, 'PERSON'), (197, 242, 'ORG'), (259, 272, 'LOC'), (17, 30, 'GPE'), (337, 346, 'PERSON'), (348, 370, 'ORG'), (407, 418, 'GPE'), (396, 405, 'GPE')]})
Grouped results
When I include even one of the incorrect sentences with several correct ones as part of the goldparse, it gives 0 for all values except token_acc.
Even if the goldparse if off by one character the result changes to 0 for P,F & R.
Eg: Predicted = (8,16,'PERSON')
GoldParse = (7,16,'PERSON')
Can someone please clarify why this is happening? I have gone through the code yet I don't understand why partially correct entities are being scored as 0 for P, R and F-Score.
Your Environment
Operating System: Ubuntu 18.04 (Using Colab)
Python Version Used: 3.6.8
spaCy Version Used: 2.1.4
Environment Information: Running on Colab